{
  "id": "flashcard-english-5-unit-15-16-17",
  "title": "English 5 Units 15+16+17",
  "subject": "english",
  "tags": ["english-5", "unit-15", "unit-16", "unit-17", "vocab"],
  "description": "Từ vựng tiếng Anh lớp 5 Unit 15 (Our health), Unit 16 (Seasons and the weather), Unit 17 (Stories for children).",
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "health (n)",
      "answer": "sức khỏe",
      "speak": "health"
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "illness (n)",
      "answer": "bệnh tật",
      "speak": "illness"
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "fever (n)",
      "answer": "sốt",
      "speak": "fever"
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "headache (n)",
      "answer": "đau đầu",
      "speak": "headache"
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "stomachache (n)",
      "answer": "đau bụng",
      "speak": "stomachache"
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "cough (n, v)",
      "answer": "ho",
      "speak": "cough"
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "sore throat (n)",
      "answer": "đau họng",
      "speak": "sore throat"
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "runny nose (n)",
      "answer": "sổ mũi",
      "speak": "runny nose"
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "cold (n)",
      "answer": "cảm lạnh",
      "speak": "cold"
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "medicine (n)",
      "answer": "thuốc",
      "speak": "medicine"
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "doctor (n)",
      "answer": "bác sĩ",
      "speak": "doctor"
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "nurse (n)",
      "answer": "y tá",
      "speak": "nurse"
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "take medicine (v)",
      "answer": "uống thuốc",
      "speak": "take medicine"
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "see a doctor (v)",
      "answer": "đi khám bác sĩ",
      "speak": "see a doctor"
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "rest (v)",
      "answer": "nghỉ ngơi",
      "speak": "rest"
    },
    {
      "id": 16,
      "question": "drink lots of water (v)",
      "answer": "uống nhiều nước",
      "speak": "drink lots of water"
    },
    {
      "id": 17,
      "question": "avoid getting sick (v)",
      "answer": "tránh bị bệnh",
      "speak": "avoid getting sick"
    },
    {
      "id": 18,
      "question": "healthy (adj)",
      "answer": "khỏe mạnh",
      "speak": "healthy"
    },
    {
      "id": 19,
      "question": "tired (adj)",
      "answer": "mệt mỏi",
      "speak": "tired"
    },
    {
      "id": 20,
      "question": "weak (adj)",
      "answer": "yếu",
      "speak": "weak"
    },
    {
      "id": 21,
      "question": "season (n)",
      "answer": "mùa",
      "speak": "season"
    },
    {
      "id": 22,
      "question": "spring (n)",
      "answer": "mùa xuân",
      "speak": "spring"
    },
    {
      "id": 23,
      "question": "summer (n)",
      "answer": "mùa hè",
      "speak": "summer"
    },
    {
      "id": 24,
      "question": "autumn (n)",
      "answer": "mùa thu",
      "speak": "autumn"
    },
    {
      "id": 25,
      "question": "winter (n)",
      "answer": "mùa đông",
      "speak": "winter"
    },
    {
      "id": 26,
      "question": "sunny (adj)",
      "answer": "trời nắng",
      "speak": "sunny"
    },
    {
      "id": 27,
      "question": "rainy (adj)",
      "answer": "trời mưa",
      "speak": "rainy"
    },
    {
      "id": 28,
      "question": "windy (adj)",
      "answer": "trời gió",
      "speak": "windy"
    },
    {
      "id": 29,
      "question": "cloudy (adj)",
      "answer": "nhiều mây",
      "speak": "cloudy"
    },
    {
      "id": 30,
      "question": "storm (n)",
      "answer": "bão",
      "speak": "storm"
    },
    {
      "id": 31,
      "question": "temperature (n)",
      "answer": "nhiệt độ",
      "speak": "temperature"
    },
    {
      "id": 32,
      "question": "wear warm clothes (v)",
      "answer": "mặc quần áo ấm",
      "speak": "wear warm clothes"
    },
    {
      "id": 33,
      "question": "go swimming (v)",
      "answer": "đi bơi",
      "speak": "go swimming"
    },
    {
      "id": 34,
      "question": "fly a kite (v)",
      "answer": "thả diều",
      "speak": "fly a kite"
    },
    {
      "id": 35,
      "question": "build a snowman (v)",
      "answer": "làm người tuyết",
      "speak": "build a snowman"
    },
    {
      "id": 36,
      "question": "jeans (n)",
      "answer": "quần bằng vải bông",
      "speak": "jeans"
    },
    {
      "id": 37,
      "question": "jumper (n)",
      "answer": "áo len cao cổ",
      "speak": "jumper"
    },
    {
      "id": 38,
      "question": "trousers (n)",
      "answer": "quần dài",
      "speak": "trousers"
    },
    {
      "id": 39,
      "question": "story (n)",
      "answer": "câu chuyện",
      "speak": "story"
    },
    {
      "id": 40,
      "question": "fairy tale (n)",
      "answer": "truyện cổ tích",
      "speak": "fairy tale"
    },
    {
      "id": 41,
      "question": "character (n)",
      "answer": "nhân vật",
      "speak": "character"
    },
    {
      "id": 42,
      "question": "king (n)",
      "answer": "vua",
      "speak": "king"
    },
    {
      "id": 43,
      "question": "queen (n)",
      "answer": "hoàng hậu",
      "speak": "queen"
    },
    {
      "id": 44,
      "question": "prince (n)",
      "answer": "hoàng tử",
      "speak": "prince"
    },
    {
      "id": 45,
      "question": "princess (n)",
      "answer": "công chúa",
      "speak": "princess"
    },
    {
      "id": 46,
      "question": "dragon (n)",
      "answer": "rồng",
      "speak": "dragon"
    },
    {
      "id": 47,
      "question": "hero (n)",
      "answer": "anh hùng",
      "speak": "hero"
    },
    {
      "id": 48,
      "question": "villain (n)",
      "answer": "nhân vật phản diện",
      "speak": "villain"
    },
    {
      "id": 49,
      "question": "magical (adj)",
      "answer": "kỳ diệu, huyền diệu",
      "speak": "magical"
    },
    {
      "id": 50,
      "question": "adventure (n)",
      "answer": "cuộc phiêu lưu",
      "speak": "adventure"
    },
    {
      "id": 51,
      "question": "lesson (n)",
      "answer": "bài học",
      "speak": "lesson"
    },
    {
      "id": 52,
      "question": "kind (adj)",
      "answer": "tử tế",
      "speak": "kind"
    },
    {
      "id": 53,
      "question": "brave (adj)",
      "answer": "dũng cảm",
      "speak": "brave"
    },
    {
      "id": 54,
      "question": "clever (adj)",
      "answer": "thông minh",
      "speak": "clever"
    },
    {
      "id": 55,
      "question": "mean (adj)",
      "answer": "độc ác",
      "speak": "mean"
    },
    {
      "id": 56,
      "question": "fight (v)",
      "answer": "chiến đấu",
      "speak": "fight"
    },
    {
      "id": 57,
      "question": "rescue (v)",
      "answer": "cứu",
      "speak": "rescue"
    },
    {
      "id": 58,
      "question": "defeat (v)",
      "answer": "đánh bại",
      "speak": "defeat"
    },
    {
      "id": 59,
      "question": "live happily ever after (phrase)",
      "answer": "sống hạnh phúc mãi mãi",
      "speak": "live happily ever after"
    }
  ]
}